[Subtitles by danielsangeo]
Okay, act calm, act calm.
If I don't act calm, they're gonna know
something's up when I walk in there.
Okay, easy, control your breathing.
Breathe normally, breathe normally.
That'll make you calm.
Oh, God, they can see me now.
Okay, keep against the wall and try and
walk straight past the front desk.
Don't make eye-contact, just walk.  WALK!
GUARD: Hey, Mr. Freeman.
DAMMIT!
GUARD: I had a bunch of messages for you,
but we had a system crash about 20 minutes ago
GUARD: and I'm still trying to find my files.
I was so close!
GUARD: Just one of those days, I guess.
GUARD: They were having some problems
down in the Test Chamber, too,
GUARD: but, I think that's all
straightened out.
GUARD: They told me to make sure
you headed down there
GUARD: as soon as you got
into your hazard suit.
Really?
Maybe I'm not fired.
In that case, let me show you what a
genius I am and look at your computer.
SCIENTIST: Someone has hidden
my glasses again.
Uh, yeah.
Let's see.
Wait a minute, this is a
Windows blue screen.
And you're typing on it like you
know what you're doing.
You're not doing anything.
SCIENTIST: Let me help you.
Shut up!
You're just looking busy. That's your
whole job, isn't it? Looking busy.
Look, you have to reboot it.
Where's the reset button?
Is this it?
[alarm sounds]
SCIENTIST: My God! What are you doing?
Well, that's not it.
GUARD: C'mon, Gordon! You tryin'
to get me into trouble?
Okay, you can all go to hell if
you're gonna act like that.
See if I ever do anything
nice for you again.
Because I won't.
SCIENTIST: As I expected.
WHAT WAS THAT?!
You tryin' to say somethin' about me?!
Man, I'll kill you!
Pricks...
Well, they've got some lip up in
here, I'll say that much.
Makes me wonder what else
they're saying behind my back.
Well, it doesn't matter.
I could take on any of them.
SCIENTIST: Freeman.
'sup, fool?
Man, someday I'm gonna own this place.
Wup, there's management.
Let me guess what they're talking about.
"You, sir, are mad! Dinosaurs are
reptiles! They must be cold-blooded!"
"Now, you listen and you listen good:
"Birds are one of the closest living
relatives to dinosaurs we have.
"And I don't need to tell you
they're all warm-blooded."
"Do you know how difficult it is to maintain
thermostasis for an animal so large?
"They're cold-blooded, I tell you!"
"Let me tell you something.
"There's evidence to suggest
that velociraptors had feathers.
"Feathers! Now, what does that tell you?"
All right, this is stupid. I may
as well go to work.
I'm glad I'm not fired.
That means I don't have to
loot the place.
Stealing from work is so much more stressful
than not stealing from work.
There's just no comparison.
Move it, blue stuff.
GUARD: I think you got the wrong
airlock, Mr. Freeman.
GUARD: You know I can't let you
through here.
Uh...
I knew that.
This is kinda awkward...
Did I really go the wrong way?
Yep, there it is: Sector B.
Man, I am tripping this morning!
Wait a second, did I see
what I think I did?
Yep, I sure did--Newton's
formula for gravitational force.
Having trouble remembering
that one, guys?
What is this? Are we back in
high school now?
My department is working on
quantum displacement.
Just what the hell are you guys doing?
Jerking around in labcoats from
the looks of things.
I just can't believe it. Those monkeys in there
are having trouble learning about gravity,
whereas I can recite the quantum chromodynamic
gauge invariant Lagrangian in my sleep!
There is no justice.
[muffled music]
Am I hearing things?
[blaring techno music]
TURN DOWN THE MUSIC, YOU FRIGGIN' BASSHEADS!
IT SOUNDS LIKE A STRIP CLUB IN HERE! GOD DAMN!
[blaring techno music]
JUST GET SOME DANCING GIRLS IN CAGES, WHY DON'T YOU?
GOOD LORD!
[blaring techno music]
[techno music fades]
MAN! Programmers...
Who knows what they're doing in there?
They're going to go deaf before the
end of the year at that rate.
Next time I have to go in there,
I'll bring some ear protection.
SCIENTIST: Ah, it's good to see you.
What?
Is he talking to me?
He's not even looking this way.
I could've sworn I heard something...
Ah, I'm losing my mind.
Well, at least it sounded friendly,
unlike that prick back at the lobby.
"This place is dead..."
Oh! I see a bowl of
noodles with my name on it.
Okay, I can do this.
The guy on the left isn't looking but the
guy on the right is a rogue element.
Uh...
Uh-oh, he's walking towards me.
Stay cool, stay cool.
Oh, man, this guy's a pro.
I can't compete with this!
I shouldn't have hesitated; I had it!
Oh well, I guess I'll have to grab
something else for breakfast,
like some oxycodone!
I think it's time to go visit my
locker, get some happy pills
and make the politics here
just float away.
SCIENTIST: Why do we all have to
wear these ridiculous ties?
Oh, you wanna know why?
I'll tell you why.
It's symbolic.
The management wants you to know
that you're their dog,
so you're wearing their leash.
You don't see me wearing a tie, do you?
You know why?
Because I'm a rebel.
The day they tried to enforce
the dress code on me,
I let them know there could be an
accident around here if that happened.
And by 'accident', I mean
'bomb the place'.
Hey, are you even listening?
Eh, forget you.
My voice falls on deaf ears.
I don't even know why I waste
my time on you sheep.
I wonder if Feynman felt the same way.
What the hell?
Whose stuff is this?
There's my name, but...
But, here's a bowling certificate,
baby pictures, blue poncho...?
WHERE'S ALL MY STUFF?!
WHERE'S MY STASH?!
This is freaking me out.
It's like everything's backwards,
and I'm not even left-handed.
Okay, I'm just gonna go to work
and hope all these problems go away.
Yeah.
Oh, come on!
Now somebody's taken my helmet!
Eh, screw it, I probably won't
need it anyway.
HEV: Welcome to the HEV Mark 4
Oh no, there's that voice.
HEV: Protective System.
HEV: For use in hazardous
environment conditions.
Shh!
HEV: High-impact reactive armor: activated;
HEV: Atmospheric contaminant
sensors: activated;
Quiet!
HEV: Vital sign monitoring: activated;
HEV: Automatic medical systems: engaged;
Wow, this suit does not shut up.
HEV: Defensive weapon selection
system: activated;
HEV: Munition level monitoring: activated;
HEV: Communications interface: online;
Okay, this thing's ridiculous,
HEV: Have a very sa--
where's the 'off' button?
[beep]
There we go.
Huh, didn't it say,
"Munitions level monitoring"?
What does that mean?
Does the left hand turn into a chaingun?
I wish!
GUARD: Go right on through, sir.
Looks like you're in the barrel today.
Oh!
Did he just say I'm in the barrel today?
Oooh, shit!
Looks like I'm not the only person
here who knows some dirty jokes.
"You're in the barrel..."
I can't believe he said that.
I bet he says that to the other scientists
and it goes right over their head.
He probably thinks I don't know
what it means either, but I do.